Okay, hello.
你好
First post-Vitram lecture, cool.
第一节Vitram课很酷
So...
那么...
We finished the whole watch me code a bunch of stuff in Java section.
我们完成了整个在Java中编写一堆代码的部分
So now we get to move into the next unit of the course, where we're going to be solving a bunch of classic data structure problems.
现在我们可以进入课程的下一单元了 在这里我们将解决一系列经典的数据结构问题
So we'll show you some other data structures, like sets, and maps, and priority queues that are not lists.
我们会向你展示一些其他的数据结构 比如集合、映射和优先队列 它们不是列表
And then we'll talk about how you implement those data structures to get good performance.
然后我们会谈论如何实现这些数据结构以获得良好的性能
And by performance, we're going to use our asymptotics tools from last time to try and measure how good our implementations actually are.
通过性能来看 我们将使用上次的渐近工具来尝试衡量我们实现的实际效果
So that we can mathematically prove to ourselves, yes, this data structure is very fast, or no, this data structure implementation is slow.
这样我们就可以在数学上证明给自己看 是的 这个数据结构非常快 或者不 这个数据结构实现很慢
So over the course of the next couple weeks, we will throw at you a bunch of different data structures.
在接下来的几周里 我们会向你介绍各种不同的数据结构
But the first one you get to see today is the kind of exotic one called disjoint sets.
但今天你要看到的第一个是一种叫做不相交集的奇特结构
So maybe you haven't seen it before.
也许你以前没见过
We'll walk you through it.
我们会带你了解它
But the philosophical idea that you'll see today, and it will come up over and over again, is that we will show you an interface.
但今天你会看到的哲学思想 而且会一次又一次地出现 是我们将向你展示的一个接口
Namely, this is what the users of the disjoint set data structure want to be able to do.
换句话说 这就是不相交集数据结构的用户希望能够做的事情
So this is the puppet show that the people inside the cave want to see.
这就是洞穴里的人们想要看到的木偶戏
And then our choice as the implementers, our design of what instance variables do we use for the data structure?
然后作为实现者 我们的选择是 我们设计数据结构要使用哪些实例变量
How do we actually build the data structure?
我们到底如何构建数据结构
to show the users what they want to see, our choice of design can have a really big influence on how fast the code is.
为了向用户展示他们想要看到的内容 我们的设计选择可以对代码的运行速度产生很大影响
Namely, if we use big theta notation, how fast or how slow the code is as the inputs get large.
也就是说 如果我们使用大O符号 随着输入规模的增大 代码的运行速度是多快或多慢
And our choice will also have a big effect on code complexity.
我们的选择还会对代码复杂度产生很大影响
So depending on what we choose, we might have an implementation that's 10 lines of code, or 100 lines of code, or 1,000 lines of code.
根据我们的选择 我们可能会有一个只有10行代码 或者100行代码 甚至是1,000行代码的实现
So we have to make the right decisions as we design this data structure to get something that is fast and hopefully also simple to write.
因此 在设计这个数据结构时 我们必须做出正确的决策 以获得既快速又希望还相对简单的编写
So that's our job today.
这就是我们今天的任务
We're going to show you the data structure.
我们将向你展示这个数据结构
We're going to tell you about what the people in the cave want to see.
我们会告诉你洞中的人们想要看到什么
And then we're going to be the monks, and we're going to choose.
然后我们将成为僧侣 我们将做出选择
Do you want to hold puppets in front of a fire?
你想在火前拿着木偶吗
Do we want to make little finger horses with our fingers?
我们想用手指做小指马吗
What are we going to do to show the people the puppet show that they want to see?
我们要怎么做才能向人们展示他们想看到的木偶戏呢
That's our job for today and for the next few weeks.
这是我们今天和未来几周的工作
And they also want to be able to ask the question, are two objects, X and Y, connected?
而且他们还想能够问这个问题 两个物体X和Y是否相连
And you have to answer true or false.
你必须回答是或否
And the tricky thing about this is that the connections can be transitive.
关键的一点是这些连接可以是传递的
So to give you an example, let's say the user says, I want to connect Russia and China.
给你个例子 比如用户说 我想连接俄罗斯和中国
That's great.
太好了
There's Russia.
有俄罗斯
There's China.
有中国
I've drawn a line to connect them.
我画了一条线连接它们
And then the user says, you know what?
然后用户说 你知道吗
I want to connect Russia and Mongolia.
我想连接俄罗斯和蒙古
That's the Mongolian flag, apparently.
这是蒙古的旗帜 显然
So we'll take Russia, we'll take Mongolia, we'll connect them.
我们会把俄罗斯和蒙古连接起来
And now we can start asking questions like, are China and Mongolia connected?
现在我们可以开始问这样的问题 中国和蒙古是否连接
And the tricky thing about this data structure is that even though they are not directly connected, they're connected through Russia.
这个数据结构的棘手之处在于 即使它们不是直接相连的 它们通过俄罗斯相连
Because China's connected to Russia, is connected to Mongolia.
因为中国连接着俄罗斯 俄罗斯连接着蒙古
So the answer to this is-connected question, your data structure needs to be able to keep track of all this stuff and answer true.
这个关于连接的问题的答案 你的数据结构需要能够追踪所有这些信息并回答是
However, if I ask, or I guess maybe I'm not gonna ask a question yet, I will say, let's connect USA and Canada.
但是 如果我问 或者也许我现在不会问问题 我会说 让我们连接美国和加拿大
So there's USA, there's Canada, I connected them.
这里有美国 有加拿大 我把它们连接起来
And if I ask, are USA and Mongolia connected?
如果我问 美国和蒙古有连接吗
Your data structure must say false, because there is no way to get between the USA and Mongolia based on my current connections.
你的数据结构必须返回false 因为根据我的当前连接方式 无法在美国和蒙古之间进行连接
However, I could also change the connections as I go.
不过 我也可以在移动时更改连接
So I could say, you know what?
我可以说 你知道吗
I'm going to connect Russia and USA, which turns out they're really close to each other on the edge of the map or something.
我要连接俄罗斯和美国 结果它们在地图边缘上真的很靠近
So maybe you connect them somehow.
也许你以某种方式连接它们
And then you ask now, are USA and Mongolia connected?
然后你现在问 美国和蒙古有连接吗
And the answer changes.
答案就变了
Because you added more connections, USA and Mongolia, they are connected now.
因为你增加了更多的连接 美国和蒙古 它们现在连接了
So now this operation should return true.
现在这个操作应该返回true
So that is the data structure that the users want to see.
这就是用户想看到的数据结构
They want to be able to connect stuff and ask you questions about connections.
他们想要能够连接东西并向你提出关于连接的问题
And you have to be able to answer those questions.
而且你必须能够回答这些问题
So it turns out this has real-world uses.
结果是这个在现实世界中有用
I won't talk about them.
我不会谈论它们
You'll see one in Homework 2.
你会在作业2中看到一个
Any questions about how this whole thing works before we try to actually write code to let the users see this show that they want to see?
在我们试图实际编写代码让用户看到他们想看的节目之前 关于整个系统是如何工作的问题吗
OK.
Anything on Zoom?
在 Zoom 上有什么吗
No?
没有
Cool.
酷
So I will first make one simplification.
我先做一个简化
And you can think about later that turns out this simplification does not lose any generality.
然后你可以想一想 结果发现这个简化并没有失去任何一般性
So the data structure works just fine, even if I simplify it a little bit.
数据结构仍然可以正常工作 即使我稍微简化了一下
So the two simplifications I'll make for today, and they won't actually affect functionality and won't be making the data structure worse, is
我今天要做的两个简化 实际上不会影响功能 也不会使数据结构变得更糟 就是
I will force all the items to be integers.
我会强制所有item都是整数
So I'm not going to say, let's connect USA.
我不会说 让我们连接美国
I'm going to say, let's connect items 0 and 1, or I'll give all the items numbers.
我会说 让我们连接第0和第1项 或者我会给所有item编号
And if you want to later, you can store a little mapping that says, oh, 0 was USA and 1 was Mongolia or something.
如果你以后想要 你可以存一个小映射 比如说 0代表美国 1代表蒙古之类的
So I will keep everything as numbers just to keep the slides clean.
我会把所有内容都保留为数字 以保持幻灯片的整洁
But you can extend the ideas from today to data structures where we are connecting USA, or pictures, or whatever else you want to connect.
但你可以把今天的想法扩展到我们要连接的数据结构 无论是美国 还是图片 或者其他任何你想连接的东西
The second thing I will do to simplify the data structure is I will force you to tell me about all the objects in advance.
我简化数据结构的第2个做法是 我会强迫你提前告诉我所有的对象
So instead of on the previous slide, where I started having flags pop out of nowhere, like, oh, here's USA and Canada,
这不同于之前的幻灯片 我开始让标志突然出现 比如 这里是美国和加拿大
and you didn't know they were going to be there, I'm going to tell you in advance there are actually seven items, 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
而你并不知道它们会出现 我会提前告诉你实际上有七个item 0、1、2、3、4、5、6
So I'll declare to you there are seven items.
我会声明有七个item
When I create this data structure for the first time, all seven items are disconnected, and then I can start connecting them.
当我第一次创建这个数据结构时 所有七个item都是断开的 然后我可以开始连接它们
So that will be the two simplifications that I'll make.
那就是我会做的两个简化
So I'll say there are seven items.
我会说有七个item
None of them are connected.
它们之间没有连接
Let's connect 0 and 1.
让我们连接0和1
OK, there's the connection.
连接完成
Let's connect 1 and 2.
让我们连接1和2
Let's connect 0 and 4.
让我们连接0和4
Let's connect 3 and 5.
让我们连接3和5
And let's ask some questions, like, are 2 and 4 connected?
然后问一些问题 比如 2和4连接吗
Well, there's 2.
嗯 有2
There's 4.
有4
They're part of the same kind of blob of connected things.
它们是连接的一种相同的东西的一部分
So the answer is true.
答案是真的
But are 3 and 0 connected?
但是3和0连接吗
Well, there's no connection between 3 and 0, so I say false.
3和0之间没有连接 所以我说是假的
But remember, connections can change over time.
但要记住 连接可以随时间改变
So I could say, let's connect 4 and 2.
我可以说 让我们连接4和2
Let's connect 4 and 6.
让我们连接4和6
Let's connect 3 and 6.
让我们连接3和6
Hooray.
万岁
And now, suddenly, if I ask if 3 and 0 are connected, the answer is now true, because there are some connections that connect 3 and 0 together.
现在 突然间 如果我问3和0是否连接 答案现在是真的 因为有一些连接将3和0连接在一起
OK, so the same thing as the China, USA, Mongolia example, but I made two simplifications to make our lives a little bit easier.
就像中国、美国、蒙古的例子一样 但我做了两个简化 让我们的生活稍微容易一点
OK.
Great.
太好了
So like we said, this is the interface.
就像我们说的 这是界面
This is what the users want to see.
这是用户想要看到的
And they do not care how you implement it.
他们不关心你如何实现它
But we care, because our choice of implementations will determine how easy it is to implement this and also how fast it is.
但我们关心 因为我们的实现选择将决定实现这个的难易程度 也决定了速度
In particular, we have to care about, remember, in the asymptotic lecture we said, what we really care about is when n grows really large.
特别是 我们要关心的是 在渐近讲座中我们说过 我们真正关心的是当n变得非常大的时候
So we have to care about, what if a user wants a disjoint set with millions of items, billions of items?
我们要关心的是 如果用户想要一个包含数百万项、数十亿项的不相交集合 我们的数据结构还能保持快速吗
Is our data structure still going to be fast?
我们的数据结构仍然会很快吗
And what if the user wants to call connect and is connected billions and billions of times?
如果用户想要调用连接 并且连接了数十亿次 我的数据结构还能保持快速吗
Can my data structure still be fast?
我的数据结构还能保持快速吗
So we need to be able to support users who want to do heavy-duty disjoint sets computations.
因此 我们需要支持那些想要进行大规模不相交集合计算的用户
And as we said earlier, the operations can be interspersed.
正如我们早些时候所说的 这些操作可以是交叉进行的
So you cannot assume they're going to connect everything first and then ask you questions.
你不能假设他们会先连好所有东西然后再来问问题
They could ask you some questions, connect some more things, and then ask you more questions, and the answers might change.
他们可能会问一些问题 接着连更多东西 然后再问更多问题 答案可能会变
So let's start digging right in.
现在让我们开始深入探讨
We'll try and think about what can we do to implement this show for the people in the cave.
我们会尝试思考如何为洞穴里的人实现这个展示
So here's the very first thing I'm going to think of, which is, well, you and I, we looked at the pictures on the slides, and we were able to answer the questions.
首先我想到的是 你和我 我们看了幻灯片上的图片 能够回答问题
Like, I showed you this picture, and I said, are 0 and 6 connected?
比如 我给你看了这张图片 然后问 0和6连通了吗
And you looked at the picture, and you said, no, they're not connected.
你看了图片 回答说 没有连通
But if I asked you, are 0 and 2 connected?
不过 如果我问你 0和2是不是连接的
You looked at the picture, and you said yes.
你看了照片 然后说是的
So what if I just told the computer, draw this picture for me?
那如果我只是告诉电脑 帮我画这个图呢
OK, but computers can't really draw pictures.
但是电脑实际上不能真的画图
So maybe I'll tell the computer, why don't you record all the lines?
也许我会告诉电脑 为什么不记录所有这些线呢
So maybe tell the computer, OK, in my data structure, I'm going to write down 0 and 1 are connected, and 1 and 2 are connected.
也许告诉电脑 在我的数据结构中 我会写下0和1是连接的 1和2是连接的
And 2 and 4 are connected.
而且2和4是连接的
So I'll write down the lines.
我会把这些句子写下来
And then when the user asks if 0 and 2 are connected, I'll somehow iterate through the lines and check if they're connected.
然后当用户问0和2是否连接时 我会以某种方式遍历这些句子 并检查它们是否连接
So you could do this.
你可以这样做
But I'm actually going to stop us right there, because this is already getting complicated.
但是我要在这里停下 因为这已经变得很复杂了
Maybe you can already feel the complexity weighing down on us.
也许你已经感受到这种复杂性在我们身上压下来了
Because if I have to keep track of all these lines, and then later I have to do some sort of complicated iteration through them and be like, well,
因为如果我必须追踪所有这些句子 然后稍后我必须通过一些复杂的迭代 并像这样说
0 is connected to 1, 1 is connected to 2, and you have to do all this computation.
0连接到1 1连接到2 而且你必须进行所有这些计算
You can imagine doing this over millions of nodes.
你可以想象在数百万个节点上执行这个操作
This is going to be complicated to write.
写这个会变得很复杂
This is going to be very slow.
这将会非常慢
And I can kind of feel that because I've seen these data structures before.
我能感觉到这一点 因为我以前见过这些数据结构
And part of going through these together is hopefully you also start seeing when things seem slow and like a bad idea.
一起经历这些的一部分是希望你也开始注意到当事情变得缓慢和不是一个好主意的时候
So we're going to stop right here.
我们就在这里停下来
We're going to go seek better and more clever implementations.
我们将寻找更好、更巧妙的实现
But if you wanted to, you could take this all the way to the end and actually build it.
但是如果你想的话 你可以一直进行下去 实际上构建它
You would just get something complicated and slow, because you have to iterate through a bunch of lines.
你只会得到一些复杂而慢的东西 因为你必须迭代一堆行
And that's not great.
而且那并不好
So the next observation, one of several clever things we'll notice, is if I look at this picture and I asked you, are 0 and 6 connected, how were you able to say no so quickly?
下一个观察 我们将注意到几个聪明的事情之一是 如果我看着这张图片 问你 0和6连接吗 你是怎么能够这么快地说不的呢
Oh, yeah, we could look at the picture.
哦 是的 我们可以看一看图片
But somehow, doesn't it feel like 0, 1, 2, and 4 are kind of part of the same team, and then 3 and 5 are part of the same team, and then 6 is off by itself?
但是不知何故 感觉0、1、2和4有点像是同一个item的一部分 然后3和5是同一个item的一部分 然后6是单独的
So when I looked at this picture, I could just say, well, 0 is part of this team on the left.
当我看这张图片时 我只能说 0是左边这个item的一部分
6 is part of this team on the right.
6 是这个item右侧的一部分
They're different, so they're not connected.
它们不同 所以它们没有连接
And the same thing when I asked you, are 0 and 2 connected?
当我问你的时候 0 和 2 是否连接
You said, well, 0 is part of this group on the left.
你说 0 是左侧这个组的一部分
2 is part of this group on the left.
2 是左侧这个组的一部分
So yes, they're connected.
是的 它们是连接的
So maybe if I look at this picture, I see, aha, instead of looking at the individual lines where I said, OK, well, 0 is connected to 1.
也许如果我看这张图片 我会看到 而不是看我说的个别线条 那么 0 就连接到 1
It's connected to 2, so it's OK.
它连接到2 所以没问题
Maybe when you looked at this and you said 0 and 2 are connected, what you really did is you just looked at this big blob over here and you said, oh, 0 and 2, they're part of the same team.
也许当你看到这个时 你说0和2连接了 你实际上只是看了这个大的团块 然后说 哦 0和2 它们是同一个item的一部分
There's connections in this.
这里有连接
team, I don't really care where they are, but they're part of the same group, so they must be connected.
item 我不太在意它们在哪里 但它们是同一个组的一部分 所以它们肯定是连接的
So what if I take that idea and I put it in a data structure?
那么如果我把这个想法放到一个数据结构中会怎么样呢
So what does that look like?
那会是什么样子呢
So here's what it might look like, which is instead of writing out all the lines and then using the lines to do some iteration, what if I just kept track of all these teams?
这可能看起来像这样 而不是写出所有的行 然后使用这些行来进行一些迭代 如果我只是跟踪所有这些item会怎么样
So I said at the beginning of the data structure,
一开始我说过 数据结构的基础是
Everybody is on their own separate team.
每个人都在自己独立的item里
Nothing is connected.
什么都没有连接
And then when I connect 0 and 1, 0 and 1 become part of the same team because they're connected.
然后当我连接 0 和 1 时 0 和 1 变成了同一个item的一部分 因为它们连接在一起
Do I care how they're connected?
我在乎它们是怎么连接的吗
Not really, because I only have to answer these true and false questions.
其实不太在乎 因为我只需要回答这些是真还是假的问题
No one's going to ask me, how are 2 and 4 connected?
没人会问我 2 和 4 是怎么连接的吗
They're just going to ask me, are 2 and 4 connected?
他们只会问我 2和4是否连接
Yes or no.
是或不是
So I'll just put them in the same team and move on with my life.
我只需把它们放在同一个item里 然后继续我的生活
Now I have to connect 1 and 2.
现在我要连接1和2
And again, I could keep tracking the lines, but that's really complicated.
而且 我可以继续跟踪线路 但那真的很复杂
So instead, what if I just said 0, 1, and 2?
我如果只说0、1和2呢
You are now part of the same team.
你现在是同一个item的一部分
How are they connected?
它们是如何连接的
Is it 0 and 2?
是 0 和 2 吗
Is it 0, 1, and 1, and 2?
是 0、1 和 1、2 连接的吗
I don't care.
我不在乎
All I care is that these three items are all connected.
我只在乎这3个item都连接了
What about 0 and 4 connecting?
那 0 和 4 连接呢
Well, then 4 joins this family, and then 3, 5, and 6 are off. by themselves.
好吧 那么 4 加入这个家庭 然后 3、5 和 6 就独自离开了
Then I connect 3 and 5, and I get the picture from before.
然后我连接3和5,得到之前的图片.
0, 1, 2, and 4, part of a team.
0、1、2和4,是一个item的一部分.
3 and 5, part of a separate team.
3和5,是一个单独item的一部分.
And then 6, all only by itself.
然后6,完全独立.
So now if I ask the question, are 2 and 4 connected, what do you do?
现在如果我问,2和4是否连接,你会怎么做?
2 and 4, you are part of the same team, so it must be true.
2和4,你们是同一个item的一部分,所以这一定是真的.
And 3 and 0, you are part of different teams, so you must be false.
3和0 你属于不同的item 所以你必须是错误的
So this seems a little bit easier to keep track of than the lines from before.
这似乎比之前的行更容易跟踪
I mean, keep going.
我的意思是 继续
OK, 4 and 2 are connected.
4和2是连接的
That one's kind of interesting.
那个有点有趣
It does nothing, because 4 and 2 were already connected.
它什么也不做 因为4和2已经连接了
They're already part of the team, so nothing actually changes.
它们已经是item的一部分 所以实际上什么也没变
What about 4 and 6?
4 和 6 呢
OK, well, now 6 joins the family.
现在 6 加入家族了
And if I connect 3 and 6, now everybody's part of one big team.
如果我连接 3 和 6 现在每个人都是一个大item的一部分
And if I ask if things are connected, I will get true.
如果我询问事物是否连接 我将得到 true
Everyone's part of the same team.
每个人都是同一个item的一部分
So that's my better approach.
这就是我的更好方法
I took the clever realization that I don't have to keep track of lines because I don't care how things are connected.
我意识到我不必追踪线路 因为我不关心事物是如何连接的
I just care true or false.
我只在乎是真是假
Are they connected?
它们连接了吗
So I can use this idea to hopefully make my code a bit simpler.
我可以用这个想法来希望让我的代码变得简单一点
OK.
That's great, it's a nice idea, but we still have to implement it.
那太棒了 这是一个好主意 但我们仍然需要实现它
So we started with the every single line, not great.
我们从每一行开始 这不太好
Then we thought about, let's just forget about how things are connected, and let's just keep track of groups and teams.
然后我们考虑过 就让我们忘记事物是如何连接的 只是记住组和item
So next question for you then is, if I want to actually program this in Java, what instance variables does my disjoint sets object have to have?
那么接下来的问题是 如果我想在Java中实际编写这个程序 我的并查集对象必须具有哪些实例变量
How do I actually keep track of this thing in memory?
我实际上如何在内存中跟踪这个东西呢
OK, so you can think about it, I don't know, 10 seconds.
你可以考虑一下 我不知道 10秒钟
What instance variables would you want to use?
你想使用哪些实例变量
You can have lists, maps, sets, arrays, integers, whatever you want, strings.
你可以有列表、映射、集合、数组、整数 任何你想要的 字符串
How would you keep track of this in a way that's hopefully easy for you to write and also efficient?
你会如何跟踪这个 希望这对你来说既容易编写又高效
So one idea that people always like to come up with is, well, sometimes people say, it looks like you have a list of sets.
人们经常想出的一个主意是 有时候人们说 看起来你有一个集合的列表
There's a set.
有一个集合
There's another set.
还有一个集合
又有一个集合
And you have a list of them.
你有一个它们的列表
So a pretty common thing that people like to suggest is, let's represent things as lists of sets.
一个人们喜欢建议的相当普遍的事情是 让我们将事物表示为集合的列表
This is what it looks like.
这就是它的样子
So I will say there is a list.
我会说有一个列表
And what's each item in the list?
每个列表项是什么
It's not a list of dogs.
这不是一份狗的列表
It's not a list of cats.
这不是一份猫的列表
It's a list of sets, each item in the list.
这是一份集合的列表 每个列表项
That's one item.
这是一个item
It's a set.
这是一个集合
That's another item.
这是另一个item
It's a set.
这是一个集合
That's another item.
那是另一个item
It's a set.
这是一个集合
So it makes sense, just taking what I saw on the slide, putting it in Java.
很合理 就是把我在幻灯片上看到的东西放到Java中
But it turns out this is another danger point, where if you make this choice and you lock it in and you start coding things, you're going to have a sad time.
但事实证明这是另一个危险点 如果你做出这个选择并锁定它 开始编写代码 你将会度过悲伤的时光
It's going to be complicated.
这会变得复杂
It's going to be slow.
这会变得慢
So here's another point where if you try this decision, and you can, but you would be doomed to failure.
这里是另一个要点 如果你尝试这个决定 你可以 但你将注定失败
So why would you be doomed to failure?
那么为什么你会注定失败呢
Now we have to start bringing back those asymptotic tools from last time to start and measure how slow is this if users want to use this?
现在我们必须开始重新引入上次的渐近工具 来衡量这个如果用户想要使用它有多慢
Sure, here it's six items, so it's not too bad.
当然 这里有6个item 所以还好
But what if I was using a million items or a billion items?
但是如果我在使用一百万个item或者十亿个item呢
How slow is this thing?
这个东西有多慢
So let's look at this case where nothing is connected.
那么让我们看看这种情况 即没有任何连接的情况
I started out with seven items.
我一开始有七个item
They are all part of their own teams.
它们都属于各自的item
And I ask you the question, are five and six connected?
我问你一个问题 5和6有关联吗
How do you tell if five and six are connected?
你如何判断5和6是否有关联
Well, remember, you don't get the pictures.
记住 你看不到图片
You're just getting this list of sets data structure.
你只是得到这个集合数据结构的列表
So what would Java have to do?
那么Java需要做什么
What would your code have to do to check if five and six are connected?
你的代码要做什么来检查5和6是否相连
Well, I don't know about you, but my code would probably do something like, I'll check the first set.
我不知道你 但我的代码可能会做类似的事情 我会检查第一组
There's no 5.
没有5
No 5.
That's not 5.
那不是5
That's not 5 either.
那也不是5
Aha.
啊哈
There's the 5.
这是 5
OK, so I found the 5.
我找到了 5
It's part of this team right here.
它就在这个item里
OK.
Now I have to find the 6.
现在我得找到 6
So I've got to go back and, are you 6?
我得回去 你是 6 吗
Nope.
不对
You 6?
你是6吗
Nope.
不对
There's the 6.
这是第6个
OK.
Which team are you in?
你在哪个队
You're in this team.
你在这个队
5 was in here.
5 在这里
6 was in here.
6 在这里
Are you the same?
你是同一个吗
No.
不行
So how did I find 5 and 6?
那我是怎么找到5和6的呢
I had to scan through the entire list to find 5 and 6, and then decide that they are not connected.
我不得不浏览整个列表找到5和6 然后确定它们没有连接
And again, you can imagine this holds true if there are a million items.
而且 你可以想象 如果有一百万个item的话 这仍然成立
And if some of them are connected, you'd have to scan the entire list to find where the item is, and then scan the entire list to find where the second item is, and then decide that they're not connected.
如果其中一些item是连接的 你就得浏览整个列表找到第一个item 然后再浏览整个列表找到第2个item 然后确定它们没有连接
So it turns out this has the overall runtime of theta n. And here I'm using theta n from the asymptotics lecture to say that
结果证明这个整体运行时间是Θ n 这里我使用Θ n 是从渐近讲座中来表示
The order of growth, if I model runtime as a function of how many things are in my input, here there are seven things, but there could have been a million or a billion.
增长的顺序 如果我把运行时间建模为输入中有多少事物的函数 这里有七个事物 但也可能有一百万个或十亿个
The runtime is going to somehow grow linearly with my input.
运行时会以某种方式与我的输入线性增长
Another way of putting it is if I double the size of my input, it will take twice as long to scan through the array and find, or scan through the list, I guess, and find the items that I'm looking for.
换句话说 如果我将输入的大小加倍 那么扫描数组并找到我正在寻找的项 或者扫描列表 我猜 并找到我正在寻找的项将需要两倍的时间
If I make my array 10 times as big, then the linear function tells me it'll take me 10 times as long to go through and find the things that I'm looking for.
如果我让我的数组变大10倍 那么线性函数告诉我需要10倍的时间来查找我正在寻找的东西
So this already has theta of n runtime.
这已经有了Θ(n)的运行时
OK.
Turns out, we can do a lot better.
事实证明 我们可以做得更好
But let's keep track of this in a table just to remind ourselves.
但让我们在表中跟踪这个 只是为了提醒自己
So we said that the operations had theta of n runtime.
我们说过 这些操作的运行时间是Θ(n)
But just to be totally honest and draw a really honest picture, theta of n, that was the worst case.
但为了完全诚实 画一个真实的图 Θ(n)其实是最坏的情况
I showed you this really bad case where all the things are separate, and the 5 and the 6, they were at the end.
我给你展示了一个真的很糟糕的情况 所有的东西都是分开的 5和6在最后
So you had to scan all the way to the end to find the 5 and the 6 and decide that they are not connected.
你得扫描到最后才能找到5和6 并确定它们不相连
I don't know, maybe someone gives you a question like, are 0 and 1 connected?
我不知道 也许有人问你一个问题 0和1是不是相连
That's probably faster.
那可能会更快
So just to be totally honest, we're going to say theta of n is the worst case, but there might be some other cases that are faster.
完全诚实地说 我们会说Θ(n)是最坏的情况 但可能还有一些其他更快的情况
Maybe someone asks you about 0 and 1, and they're right at the start of the list.
也许有人问你关于0和1 而它们正好位于列表的开头
That might be faster.
那可能更快一些
So I'll just say big O of n, remembering that big O is somehow less than or equal to the order of growth
我只会说O(n) 记住O是以某种方式小于或等于增长的顺序
If I model time versus size of the input, or size of the input versus time, if I model that graph, I expect to see a line in the worst case.
如果我建模时间与输入大小或输入大小与时间的关系 如果我建模那个图 我期望在最坏的情况下看到一条线
But maybe there are some cases where the performance is a little bit better.
但也许有些情况下性能会稍微好一些
That's why I'll say big O here.
这就是为什么我在这里说O的原因
But for today, all I have to know is that this is somehow linear time performance.
但对于今天 我只需要知道这在某种程度上是线性时间性能
I don't like it.
我不喜欢它
It's slow.
它很慢
It's complicated.
它很复杂
I have to write a lot of code.
我得写很多代码
Lists of sets are complicated.
列表和集合的处理很复杂
And I have to make
而且我还得做一些其他的
All right, I have big old runtime, so it's slow.
好吧 我有一个古老的运行时 所以它很慢
So again, just by choosing this Java data structure list of sets, you are doomed to bad performance.
再说一遍 仅仅通过选择这个Java数据结构中的集合列表 你就注定会遇到性能问题
So we've got to pick something better.
我们必须选择更好的东西
OK, so how do we pick something better?
那么我们如何选择更好的东西呢
So here's the second idea, which is kind of clever.
这里是第2个想法 有点巧妙
So here, instead of saying, and this is like number two of a list of clever ideas that we're showing you today, but as you keep going and developing these yourselves, maybe you'll start seeing these too.
这里 不是说 这是今天我们向你展示的巧妙想法的第2个 但随着你不断地深入发展 也许你也会开始注意到这些
So the second clever idea, maybe you spotted it earlier, is let's not have a list of sets.
第2个巧妙的想法 也许你早就注意到了 那就是不要有一个集合列表
Because a list of sets, we just saw, it's complicated, it's slow.
因为我们刚刚看到 集合列表很复杂 而且很慢
What if I instead had an array, and then in my array, because my array has indices, I say, in index 0, I'm going to write down the team that item 0 belongs to.
如果我反而有一个数组 然后在我的数组中 因为我的数组有索引 我会说 在索引0 我会写下item 0属于的item
And in index 1, I'm going to write down the team that item 1 belongs to.
而在索引1 我会写下item 1属于的item
And in index 2, I'll write down the team that item 2 belongs to, and so forth.
在索引2 我会写下item 2属于的item 依此类推
So what are these numbers representing?
那么这些数字代表什么呢
Well, if you look, index 0, 1, 2, 4, they all have the same number.
如果你看 索引0、1、2、4 它们都有相同的数字
Why?
为什么
Because they are all part of the same team.
因为它们都属于同一个item
And index 3 and index 5, you have the same number because you're part of the same team.
在索引3和索引5 你们有相同的编号 因为你们是同一个item的一部分
And index 6, you have a number all by yourself because you're part of a team by yourself.
而在索引 6 你有一个数字 因为你是一个人独自组成的item
Nobody else has the number 6.
没有其他人有编号6
So here I'm choosing this implementation where I just have a single array of integers.
我选择了这种实现方式 我只有一个整数数组
And if you think about it, array of integers, a lot easier to write than lists of sets.
如果你想想 整数数组比集合列表更容易编写
Here, all I have to do is keep track of which team every item is in.
在这里 我只需要跟踪每个item属于哪个item
And just as a quick note, these numbers, I kind of picked them at random.
还有一个小提示 这些编号 我随机挑选的
I could have chosen, for example, to put 9, 9, 9, and 9.
我本可以选择 例如 放置9 9 9和9
Or I could have chosen to put 200, 200, 200, 200.
或者我可以选择放置200 200 200 200
It doesn't really matter.
其实并不重要
All that I care about is that the numbers are the same, which tells me that they are part of the same group.
我关心的只是数字相同 这告诉我它们是同一组的一部分
OK.
So that's my next choice.
这是我的下一个选择
Now I have to think about how fast are the operations.
现在我必须考虑操作有多快
So in this case, how fast is it to tell?
在这种情况下 告诉的速度有多快呢
And you can try and think, predict if you know the answer.
而且你可以尝试思考 预测如果你知道答案的话
How fast is it, maybe in terms of asymptotic runtime, maybe just a gut feeling, fast or slow, how fast is it to tell if two items are part of the same set?
告诉的速度有多快 也许从渐近运行时间的角度来看 也许只是一种直觉感觉 快还是慢 告诉2个item是否属于同一集合 有多快
In other words, to tell me if two items are connected.
换句话说 告诉我2个item是否相连
So if I ask that true or false question, are 0 and 4 connected, how fast is it?
如果我问一个真假问题 0和4是否相连 它有多快
Is it linear, where I have to scan the whole array?
是线性的吗 我必须扫描整个数组
Is it worse than linear, where I have to iterate and check a bunch of things?
还是更糟糕的是 我必须迭代并检查一堆东西
Is it faster than linear?
它比线性更快吗
Thoughts?
你有什么想法
Here, I'll do a vote.
这里 我来做个投票
Who thinks it's linear and I have to scan a bunch of things to find it?
谁认为它是线性的 我必须扫描一堆东西才能找到它
Who thinks it's slower than linear?
谁认为它比线性慢
I have to do a bunch of iteration.
我必须进行一系列的迭代
Who thinks it's faster than linear and I don't even have to scan anything?
谁认为它比线性更快 而且我甚至不用扫描任何东西
Oh.
哦
So why is it faster than linear?
那为什么它比线性更快呢
Because if I ask you, is 0 and 4 connected, all I have to do is I have to look up item 0 in the array.
因为如果我问你 0和4是否连接 我只需要查找数组中的第0项
You are team 4.
你是第4队
And I look up item 4.
然后我查找第4项
You are also team 4.
你也是第4队
You're part of the same group, so you're connected.
你们是同一个item的 所以你们是相连的
And how long did that take?
那花了多长时间
I did not have to scan the array.
我不需要扫描整个数组
So even if this array had a million items, a billion items, two billion items, it would be the exact same time.
即使这个数组有一百万项 十亿项 两十亿项 时间都是一样的
I just checked one, two things in the array, and I'm done.
我只检查了数组中的一两个事物 然后就完成了
So it turns out the isConnected operation is now constant time.
结果是 isConnected 操作现在是常数时间
It does not grow as a factor of the, as, how do I say this?
它不会随着 怎么说呢 不会随着因素增长
It does not grow as the input gets larger.
随着输入规模的增大 它不会增长
So whether my input is 7 items, or a million items, or a trillion items, it doesn't matter.
无论我的输入是7个item 还是一百万个item 或者一万亿个item 都没关系
The isConnected operation is always constant time.
isConnected 操作始终是常数时间
I look, for example, are 3 and 6 connected?
例如 我看 3和6是否连接
3, you are part of team 5.
3 你是5队的一部分
6, you are part of team 6.
6 你是6队的一部分
I look at two numbers every time.
我每次看两个数字
5 and 6, not part of the same team.
5和6 不是同一个item的一部分
You are not connected.
你没有连接
And I say false.
而且我说的是假的
That's pretty quick.
那很快
I like that.
我喜欢那个
So we went from linear time, where I had to scan.
我们从线性时间转变 我必须扫描
Is the 5 in here?
这里有5吗
I went from having to scan all the way through to having this array, where I can just immediately pick out two items and answer if they're part of the same team.
我从不得不全部扫描到拥有这个数组 我可以立即挑出2个item并回答它们是否属于同一item
That's pretty cool.
那挺酷的
So just by changing the underlying data structure, I went from linear time, isConnected operations, to constant time, isConnected operations.
只是通过更改底层数据结构 我从线性时间的isConnected操作转变为常数时间的isConnected操作
So why not stop here?
那为什么不就到这里呢
Why is this lecture going on for another half an hour?
为什么这讲座还要继续半个小时
Well, that's because what about the connect operation?
那是因为关于连接操作的问题
Oh, OK.
哦 好的
Well, the connect operation, we have a problem.
连接操作 我们有一个问题
Because what if, let's say I wanted to connect 0 and 5?
因为如果 比方说我想连接0和5
Well, to connect 0 and 5, I have to take all the items that I have here
好吧 要连接0和5 我必须拿走这里所有的item
numbered as team number 4.
标记为item编号4
And I have to take all the items in 5's group.
并且我必须取出5组的所有item
Here I've numbered a team number 5.
这里我给item编号了5号
And I have to make sure they all have the same number, namely that they are all part of the same group.
而且我必须确保它们都有相同的编号 也就是它们都是同一组的一部分
So if I wanted to connect 0 and 5, I would have to take all the people who are in team 4 and change their team number to 5.
如果我想连接0和5 我就必须把所有在4号item的人都改成5号
This way, 0, 1, 2, 4, and 3, and 5, they all have number 5.
这样 0、1、2、4、3和5 它们都有编号5了
Right?
对吧
So this representation would not have 0 and 5 connected.
这种表示法是不能把0和5连接起来的
If I wanted to connect 0 and 5, these two teams have to unify into one big team.
如果我想连接0和5 这2个item就必须统一成一个大item
And to do that, I have to take everyone from the first team, 4, 4, 4, 4, and change the number to 5, 5, 5, 5.
为了做到这一点 我必须把第一队的每个人 4 4 4 4 都改成5 5 5 5
This way, everyone in this now unified team has number 5.
这样 现在这个统一的item里每个人都是5号
So that's what I'd have to fix.
这就是我要修复的问题
So now, again, question for you is, how long, asymptotically, maybe just feeling it out, how fast is it to do this connect operation?
现在 再次问你 这个连接操作要多久 渐近地 也许只是感觉一下 有多快
Is it constant?
是常数时间吗
Regardless of how big the input is, this will always be fast.
无论输入有多大 这都会很快
Is it linear, in the sense that I'm going to have to look at every item in the array?
是线性的吗 也就是说我要查看数组中的每个项吗
Or in the sense that if my array gets twice as big, then this will take twice as long.
如果我的数组变成两倍大 那么这将花费两倍的时间
Is it worse than linear?
它比线性更糟吗
If I double the input, it gets way, way, way slower.
如果我把输入翻倍 它会变得慢得多 慢得多 慢得多
What do we think?
我们怎么看
I'll go backwards this time.
这次我会倒着来
Who thinks it's constant?
谁认为它是常数
No matter what happens, I can do this instantly, regardless of how big the array is.
不管发生什么 我都可以立即做到这一点 不管数组有多大
Who thinks it's linear?
谁认为这是线性的
I have to do some sort of scan.
我得做某种扫描
Anyone think it's slower than linear, where if I have to do extra iterations, it's even slower?
有人觉得比线性慢吗 如果我必须做额外的迭代 它会更慢吗
I like linear, too.
我也喜欢线性
So that's what the people in person said.
这就是亲自说的
So I think it's linear, because you have to start at 0, 1, 2.
我认为这是线性的 因为你必须从0、1、2开始
And any time you see a 4, you have to change it to a 5.
每当你看到一个4 你就得把它变成一个5
So I have to be like, are you 4?
我得像这样 你是4岁吗
Oh, you are.
哦 是的
Change it to 5.
把它改成5
You're 4.
你是4岁
Change it to 5.
把它改成5
You are also 4.
你也是4岁
Change it to 5.
把它改成5
OK, you're not 4.
你不是4
You are 4.
你是4
Change it to 5.
将其更改为5
OK, you're not 4.
你不是4
You're not 4.
So I have to scan all the way through.
我必须一直扫描
And if this array were huge, I'd have to scan all the way through, change all the 4s to 5.
如果这个数组很大 我必须一直扫描 将所有的4都改成5
So this idea, I call it quick find disjoint sets.
这个想法 我称之为快速查找不相交集
Why do I call it quick find?
为什么我称之为快速查找
Because finding if two things are connected is quick.
因为查找两个事物是否连接很快
All I have to do is look for two things in the array, check if they're equal, part of the same team, yes or no.
我只需要在数组中查找两个事物 检查它们是否相等 是否属于同一个item 是或否
Super quick.
超级快
Theta of 1.
Θ(1)
However, if I want to check if two things are connected, look, I have to start at the 0th item and go all the way through the array.
但是 如果我想检查两个事物是否连接 看 我必须从第0个item开始并遍历整个数组
And any time I see a 4, I have to change it to a 5, or whichever teams I am connecting.
每当我看到一个4的时候 我就得把它变成5 或者连接的任何item都是这样
So.
I call this quick find because isConnected, very, very fast.
我把这个叫做快速查找 因为 isConnected 非常非常快
Connect, kind of slow.
连接 有点慢
So I call this quick find.
我把这个叫做快速查找
OK.
Back to our picture.
回到我们的图片
We had lists of sets DS.
我们有一堆集合数据结构
That was one idea for how to show the puppet show.
这是一个展示木偶戏的想法
That was one of our plans for showing people the disjoint sets show.
这是我们展示不相交集的计划之一
And that one had slow runtime.
这个运行时间很慢
Connect was theta n I had to scan.
Connect是Θ(n)我不得不扫描的
isConnected, big O of n, sorry, I had to scan.
isConnected O(n) 抱歉 我不得不扫描
QuickFindDS, that was the one we just built with the arrays, and everyone has a team number.
QuickFindDS 那是我们刚刚用数组构建的那个 每个人都有一个item号码
Well, that had a very fast isConnected operation, theta of 1.
好吧 那个 isConnected 操作非常快 是 Θ（1）的
But the connect operation required going through the entire array, and that was theta of n. So in my table, I now have two different ways to show people the disjoint sets show to implement the interface.
但是连接操作需要遍历整个数组 这是 Θ（n）的 在我的表中 我现在有两种不同的方式来向人们展示不相交集显示如何实现接口
One of them is slow.
其中一种很慢
One of them is a little bit better.
其中一种稍微好一点
But it turns out we can do even better than this, because this one still has kind of a slow connect operation.
但事实证明我们可以做得更好 因为这个仍然有一种相当慢的连接操作
So I'm going to get this even better using another clever idea.
我要用另一个聪明的想法把它做得更好
And we'll get a third way to do it.
我们将得到第三种方法来做这件事
OK.
So just to kind of quickly debrief on what we've done so far, we started with lines and boxes.
简单来说 我们目前所做的就是 我们从线条和方框开始
Let's write down the lines.
我们先写下线条
And let's think about, let's use the lines to compute if things are connected.
然后我们想想 让我们用这些线条来计算物体是否相连
And we just gave up.
但我们就放弃了
That was too complicated.
那太复杂了
Then we did a list of sets.
然后我们做了一个集合的列表
This was slow, even though it was intuitively simple, because now I have to iterate through the sets.
这个慢 尽管直觉上很简单 因为现在我必须遍历集合
Do you have the 6?
你有这个6吗
That's kind of slow.
有点慢
Then we came up with Quick Find.
然后我们想出了快速查找
Finding things was fast.
找东西很快
Ah, you're item two.
啊 你是第2项
You're team two.
你是第2队
You're connected.
你已连接
But if I want to connect everyone in team two with everyone with team three, I have to change all the twos to threes, and that's very slow.
但是 如果我想将第2队的每个人与第3队的每个人连接起来 我必须将所有的2改成3 这很慢
So let's try to do a little bit better.
让我们试着做得更好一点
And this time, instead of throwing out this array idea, I'm actually going to keep it around.
而这一次 与其抛弃这个数组的想法 我实际上会保留它
I'm going to say, you know what?
我要说 你知道吗
Keeping these things in an array, I like that because it's simple.
把这些东西放在一个数组里 我喜欢 因为它很简单
In fact, when you implement this in lab, hint, you're implementing this in lab, all you have to do is you just have to write a single integer array.
实际上 当你在实验室里实现这个时 提示 你在实验室里实现这个 你所需要做的就是写一个整数数组
That's kind of nice.
这有点不错
However, instead of storing team numbers, which we just saw is slow because you have to change all the twos to a three, what if I store something a little bit more radical and different
然而 不是存储item编号 我们刚刚看到这样做很慢 因为你必须把所有的2改成3 而是存储一些更激进和不同的东西
So that instead of changing all the 0's to 3's on this slide, they're all team 0.
与其在这张幻灯片上把所有的 0 改成 3 它们都是item 0
I had to make them all team 3.
我不得不把它们全部变成item 3
What if I could figure out a way to store an array of integers, keeping track of set membership, so that if I want to merge two sets together,
如果我能找到一种方法来存储整数数组 跟踪集合成员关系
I want two teams to unify, it just takes a single value being changed instead of taking four or n values being changed.
这样如果我想要合并两个集合 让2个item统一 只需要改变一个值而不是改变四个或 n 个值
Turns out, this is a pretty tricky challenge.
事实证明 这是一个相当棘手的挑战
You can play with it at home if you want to.
如果你想的话 你可以在家里试试
Probably live, we're not going to have time.
可能直播时我们没时间
But I don't know.
但我不知道
Anyone see anything super interesting?
有人看到什么超级有趣的东西吗
I don't know.
我不知道
Because the problem is here, I have to change all the 0's to a 3.
因为问题就在这里 我得把所有的0都改成3
So it turns out, this one requires another
结果是 这个需要另外一种
Clever trick that maybe you don't see right away, but the more practice we get, maybe you'll start to see it.
巧妙的技巧 也许你一开始看不出来 但是我们练得越多 也许你会开始看到
So the radical different idea is instead of saying everyone is part of a team, namely you're part of team three and you're part of team three,
一个截然不同的想法是 而不是说每个人都是item的一部分 也就是你是item 3的一部分
I am actually going to do something a little bit different, which is I'm going to give every item a parent.
你是item3的一部分 我实际上会做一些有点不同的事情 就是给每个item一个父项
So instead of saying,
所以不是说
Zoom, while I do a quick change to myself, tell me how you're going to make this connect operation work.
Zoom 我在迅速改变自己的同时 告诉我你打算如何让这个连接操作起作用
Okay, go.
开始
Test, test, test, test.
测试 测试 测试 测试
I think it's good.
我觉得还不错
Thank you.
谢谢
OK.
Are we back on Zoom?
我们回到 Zoom 上了吗
OK.
How much was missed?
错过了多少
It started at 48.
它从 48 开始
OK.
Entire introduction slide.
整个介绍幻灯片
No.
不
Can you explain it again?
你能再解释一遍吗
Ah, OK.
啊 好的
So I'll explain it.
我会解释一下
If you heard it, you can think about the question I just posed.
如果你听到了 你可以考虑一下我刚刚提出的问题
So was it this slide that was confusing?
那么是这张幻灯片让你感到困惑了吗
OK, so previous approach.
先前的方法
In one minute, I said that everybody in the array
在一分钟内 我说过数组中的每个人
The value that you write for the item is the team number that they belong to.
你为item写的值是他们所属的item编号
So 0, you belong to team number 3.
所以 0 你属于第3个item
And 1, you belong to team number 3.
而 1 你也属于第3个item
The new idea for folks on Zoom is that here, instead of saying the team number that you belong to, you assign every item a parent.
在Zoom上的新想法是 这里 与其说你属于item编号 不如给每个item分配一个父项
So you say, instead of 0, or I guess 2, you belong to team 3, you say 2, you belong to item 1.
你说 不是0 或者我想是2 你属于item3 你说2 你属于item1
So whichever team item 1 is in, you're part of the same team, because you are item 1's subordinate.
无论item1在哪个item 你都是同一个item的一部分 因为你是item1的下属
So if I look in the array, I look up index 2, it says number 1.
如果我查看数组 我查找索引2 它说编号1
What does that mean?
那是什么意思
It doesn't mean you're part of team number 1.
这并不意味着你是第1个item的一部分
It doesn't mean you're number 1.
这并不意味着你是第1个
It means you're a subordinate of item 1.
这意味着你是item 1的下属
And then I can look at item 1, and it says, 1, you are a subordinate of 0.
然后我可以看item 1 它说 1 你是0的下属
And then I look at 0, and the negative number tells me that 0 is the boss.
然后我看0 负数告诉我0是老板
It's the big boss of this team.
他是这个item的大老板
And the negative 1 tells me 0, you are no subordinate.
而负1告诉我0 你没有下属
You are the boss.
你是老板
You don't belong to anybody.
你不属于任何人
And this holds for all the other ones in the array, too.
这对数组中的所有其他项也适用
So 4, you belong to item 0.
所以4 你属于第0项
So I look up 4.
我查找4
The number 0 tells me 4, you are a subordinate of item 0.
数字0告诉我4 你是第0项的下属
And five, I look it up.
而5 我查找它
You're a subordinate of item three.
你是第3项的下属
And three, you are no subordinate.
而3 你不是下属
You're the boss.
你是老大
So we put a negative one there to indicate that.
我们在那里放了一个负1来表示
And six, you're the boss of your own team.
然后6 你是你自己item的老大
There's a negative one.
这里有一个负1
How do I know that six has no subordinates?
我怎么知道6没有下属
How do I know that nobody else belongs to six?
我怎么知道没有其他人属于6
I scan through the array.
我扫描整个数组
No sixes.
没有6
So nobody belongs to six in this case.
在这种情况下没有人属于6
OK, was that sufficient for the Zoom people?
这对Zoom的人来说足够了吗
OK, so the question then is, if I have this data structure, how do you make the connect operation work?
那么问题是 如果我有这个数据结构 你怎么使连接操作生效
At this point, I'm just going to have to spoil it for time.
到这个点上 我只好为了时间而泄密了
OK, so.
The first thing we could do, and the first thing that we asked you to try and think about here, is how do you change the array?
我们可以做的第一件事 也是我们要求你尝试思考的第一件事是 如何改变数组
We have this array of numbers, which is equivalent to this picture you see.
我们有这个数字数组 它等价于你看到的这张图片
How do I change the array, or how do I change the picture, in order to connect 5 and 2?
我怎么改变数组 或者怎么改变图片 以便连接5和2
I want 3 and 5, this team, and I want the 0, 1, 2, 4 team to be part of the same family.
我想要3和5 这个item 我想要0、1、2、4这个item成为同一个家庭的一部分
I want them to unify into one big team.
我希望它们统一成一个大item
So what numbers do I have to change?
那么我需要改变哪些数字呢
Keeping in mind that I'm no longer keeping track of team numbers, but I am keeping track of which every item belongs to, or what item every item belongs to.
记住 我不再追踪item编号 但我确实追踪每个item属于哪个 或者每个item属于什么item
So everyone belongs to another item, or is a subordinate of the other item.
每个人都属于另一个item 或者是另一个item的下属
So the key idea, oh, I'm running short on time.
关键思想是 哦 时间不太够了
is why not set ID of 5 to 2?
为什么不把 ID 设置为 5 到 2 呢
We can try that.
我们可以尝试一下
We could say, ID of 5, you were 3, but I want to connect 5 to 2.
我们可以说 ID 为 5 你是 3 但我想连接 5 到 2
So why not just do this?
那为什么不直接这样做呢
Well, if I do that, I'm saying that 5, instead of belonging to 3, now you belong to 2.
好吧 如果我那样做 我是在说 5 不再属于 3 现在你属于 2
So look, 5 belongs to 3.
所以看 5 属于 3
Now it belongs to 2.
现在它属于 2
And you get this data structure.
而且你得到了这个数据结构
Because 5 now belongs to 2.
因为 5 现在属于 2
But this is a problem.
但这是个问题
Because look at 3.
因为看看 3
It has been orphaned all by itself.
它已经被孤立了
It's so lonely.
它好孤单
And this is not correct.
而且这不正确
Because remember, if I unify 5 and 2, I want all of these items, including 3, to be part of the same happy family.
因为记住 如果我统一5和2 我希望所有这些item 包括3 都成为同一个幸福的大家庭的一部分
And if I just connect 5 to 2, that would not be the case.
而且如果我只连接5到2 那就不会是这种情况
I would leave 3 lonely by itself.
我会让3孤单地独自一人
And that's too sad.
那太可悲了
So we can't have that.
我们不能这样
So instead,
相反地,
of setting 5's ID to 2, we need to do something a little bit different, which is we actually need to climb the tree.
将设置 5 的 ID 为 2 我们需要做一点不同的事情 就是我们实际上需要爬树
And we need to say, 5, you're not the boss, but your team has a boss.
而且我们需要说 5 你不是老板 但是你的item有个老板
So we climb 5.
我们爬 5
You belong to 3.
你属于 3
3, you're the boss.
3 你是老板
And then I do the same thing for 2.
然后我对 2 做同样的事情
I say, 2, you're not the boss.
我说 2 你不是老板
1, you belong to 1.
1 你属于1
1, you're not the boss.
1 你不是老板
You belong to 0.
你属于0
0, you're the boss.
0 你是老板
So what I'm actually going to do is I'm going to set the root of 5, namely the boss of 5's team.
我实际上要做的是设置5的根 即5的item的老板
That's 3.
就是3
Right now, you belong to nobody.
现在 你属于没有人
Look, 3, negative 1, you belong to nobody.
看 3 负1 你属于谁都不属于
I'm going to set 3's boss.
我要设3的老板
to 2's boss.
给2的老板
So 3 used to belong to nobody.
所以3以前是无主之物
Now you are a subordinate of 0.
现在你是0的下属
So I change, actually, the root of 5 to be under the root of 2.
我实际上改变了5的根 让它处于2的根下
See it?
看见了吗
See I'm going back and forth.
看 我来回走
OK.
So that's the idea.
这就是主意
Every time you want to connect things, you need to climb the tree.
每次你想连接东西 你都需要爬树
Say, ah, 3's the boss.
比方说 3是老大
I climb this tree, 0 is the boss, and you both can't be bosses because we're going to unify you.
我爬这棵树 0是老大 而且你们俩都不能当老大 因为我们要把你们统一起来
So 0, you're the new true boss, and we'll hang 3, the old boss, under 0.
0 你是新的真正老大 我们会把3 老老大 吊在0下面
That's the idea.
这就是主意
That's how we're going to make connections work.
这就是我们让连接发挥作用的方式
That's what we did.
这就是我们所做的
We made the root of 5 into a subordinate of the root of 2.
我们将5的根变成了2的下属
There were two bosses.
有两个老板
We can no longer have two bosses.
我们不能再有两个老板
So 3, you're one of the bosses.
所以3 你是其中一个老板
We demote you.
我们降职你
You're no longer a boss.
你不再是老板了
You now belong to item 0, who is the true mega boss of this entire set.
你现在属于item 0 他是整个集合的真正大老板
So how does this work?
那这是怎么运作的
How fast is it?
它有多快
We need to do the same analysis as before.
我们需要做与之前相同的分析
So at first, it might seem like this seems a little bit faster.
起初 这似乎会快一点
Like, how did I connect things?
我是怎么连接这些东西的
I didn't have to scan the whole array.
我不必扫描整个数组
I just had to climb this tree and climb this tree to find the bosses.
我只需爬这棵树 一直爬这棵树找到老板们
However, what if my tree looked like this?
但是 如果我的树看起来像这样呢
So what if, after doing a bunch of connect operations, my tree looked like this?
那么 如果在进行了一堆连接操作之后 我的树变成了这样呢
This is a very tall tree.
这是一棵非常高的树
And in this case, how long would it take to connect two items?
在这种情况下 连接2个item需要多长时间呢
And how long would it take to check if two items are connected?
检查两个物品是否连接需要多长时间
So it turns out, if my tree looks like this, the climbing is going to be very slow.
原来 如果我的树看起来像这样 攀爬会变得非常慢
Because if I ask you to connect something, I don't know, maybe I have another item 5 floating around somewhere, and I ask you to connect 5 and 4, what would you have to do?
因为如果我让你连接一些东西 我不知道 也许我有另一个item5漂浮在某个地方 然后我让你连接5和4 你得做什么
You'd have to start at 4 and be like, you're not the boss.
你得从4开始 然后说 你不是老板
You belong to 3.
你属于3
You belong to 2.
你属于2
You belong to 1.
你属于1
You belong to 0.
你属于0
Aha, 0 is the boss.
0就是老板
So I have to climb this very long tree to find that 0 is the boss, and then hang some other item under 0.
我必须爬这棵非常长的树 找出0是老板 然后在0下面挂一些其他的东西
So it turns out if I want to connect two things, in the worst case, I'd have to climb this very, very long tree.
结果是 如果我想连接两个东西 在最坏的情况下 我得爬这棵非常非常长的树
And if I have n items, how long can this tree be?
如果我有n个物品 这棵树可以有多长呢
It could be length n if my tree is a very, very long tree like this.
如果我的树像这样非常非常长 那么它可能是长度为n的
So it turns out this is theta and runtime.
结果是这是Θ 和运行时间
How about if two items are connected?
两个物品连接会怎样呢
Like, for example, how do I check if 4 and 3 are connected?
就像 例如 我如何检查4和3是否相连
So maybe if the first one didn't totally make sense, try and wrap your head around this one.
如果第一个没有完全明白 那就尝试理解这个问题吧
How do I check if 4 and 3 are connected?
我如何检查4和3是否相连
Well, I have to start at 4 and be like, who's the boss of 4?
我必须从4开始 看看谁是4的老板
4.
Nope.
不
不是
Nope.
0 is the boss.
0 就是老大
Who is the boss of 3?
3 是老大吗
3.
Nope.
不是
不行
0 is the boss.
0 是老大
So to find out if two things are connected, I have to climb the tree twice, see if they have the same boss.
要查两次树才知道两个东西是否连接 看它们是否有相同的老大
And if they do, that's how I know that they're connected.
如果是 那就知道它们是连接的
And in the worst case, climbing a very ugly, tall tree like this could take theta n time.
而且在最坏的情况下 像这样爬一棵非常丑陋、又高的树可能需要 Θ(n) 的时间
Because if I have n items, this tree would have n height, be a very tall tree.
因为如果我有 n 个item 这棵树的高度就是 n 是一棵非常高的树
So I call this approach quick union.
我称这种方法为快速联合
And at first, it seems like quick union is not great, because the connect operation and the isConnected operations are both theta of n. And that's because my trees were kind of ugly like this.
起初 快速联合看起来并不是很好 因为连接操作和 isConnected 操作都是Θ(n) 这是因为我的树看起来有点丑 就像这样
So the final improvement we have to make is, if only we could avoid trees that look tall like this, then maybe we have something on our hands.
最后我们需要做的改进是 如果我们能避免像这样高的树 也许我们手头就有了什么
Because remember, on this slide, the tree was kind of short, and things were great.
因为记住 在这张幻灯片上 树看起来有点矮 情况就很好
I like when the tree is like this, because here I didn't have to climb a very tall tree.
我喜欢树是这样的 因为在这里我不必爬很高的树
And climbing tall trees is exhausting.
爬高树太累了
But on here, I had a tall tree.
但在这里 我有一个高的树
So how do I avoid the tall trees to make this work?
那么 如何避免高树以使这项工作成功
So I'm going to call this quick union using this tree idea.
我要用这个树的概念来快速实现并查集
Now I'm going to add one more approach called weighted quick union.
现在我要添加一种叫做加权快速并查集的方法
And this is going to finally give us our state-of-the-art data structure.
这最终将给我们带来最先进的数据结构
So to do it, I'm going to give you a choice.
要做的就是 我给你一个选择
Do I have time to give you a choice?
我有时间给你选择吗
I'll give you a very, very quick choice, which is, remember, we wanted to connect 2 and 5.
我会给你一个非常非常快的选择 就是 记住 我们想要连接2和5
And the way to do that, I don't just connect 2 directly to 5.
连接它们的方式 我不只是直接将2连接到5
That would orphan 2, or it would orphan the nodes.
那将会使2成为孤儿 或者会使节点成为孤儿
We don't want that.
我们不想要那样
So instead, if I want to connect 2 and 5, I need to climb all the way to the top of 2 and find 0.
如果我想连接2和5 我需要一直爬到2的顶部找到0
You're the boss.
你是老大
I need to climb all the way to 5's boss, which is 3.
我需要一直爬到5的老大那里 也就是3
And I need to say, well, 0 is a boss, 3 is a boss.
然后我需要说 0是老大 3也是老大
You can't both be bosses, because we're going to make one big team.
你们不能同时做老大 因为我们要成为一个大item
So one of you needs to be hung underneath the other.
你们中的一个需要挂在另一个下面
So my question for you is, which do you like better?
我的问题是 你更喜欢哪一个
Do you like taking 3 and making it no longer a boss, hanging it underneath 0?
你喜欢把 3 变成不再是老大 挂在 0 的下面吗
That's the choice up here.
这是这里的选择
Or do you like taking 0 and saying, 0, you're no longer the boss.
还是你喜欢把 0 拿走 说 0 你不再是老大
I'm going to hang you as a subordinate of 3.
我会把你挂在 3 的下属
Which of these do you like better?
你更喜欢哪一个
Which of these do you think gives you better runtime?
你认为这些哪个能在运行时表现更好
Who likes the top one, where I take 3 and I make it 0 subordinate?
谁喜欢顶部那个 我拿3变成0从属
You like that.
你喜欢那个
Does anyone like the bottom one, where I take 0, make it 3 subordinate?
有人喜欢底部那个 我拿0变成3从属
OK.
So why did you like the top one?
那么你为什么喜欢顶部那个
Well, I like it because the tree is less tall.
我喜欢它因为树不太高
So in this case, the tree ends up being just 1, 2, 3 layers.
在这种情况下 树最终只有1、2、3层
And we'll make that more explicit in future lectures.
在未来的讲座中 我们将更明确这一点
Whereas in this bottom one, the tree has 1, 2, 3, 4 layers.
而在底部的这个例子中 树有1、2、3、4层
The climbing takes a bit longer because the bottom tree is taller.
由于底部的树更高 攀爬需要更长的时间
So it turns out the final trick we have to do to actually make a state-of-the-art quick union data structure for disjoint sets is,
事实证明 我们要为不相交集合创建一种最先进的快速联合数据结构的最后一招是
when we hang two trees together, when we want to do this connect operation, you should always take the smaller tree and put it underneath the larger tree.
当我们将两棵树连接在一起时 进行这个连接操作时 应始终选择较小的树 并将其放在较大的树的下面
So just like before here, where I took the smaller tree, namely 3, and I made it a subordinate of the larger tree,
就像在这里一样 我选取了较小的树 即3 然后将其作为较大树的从属关系
which was the one anchored at 0, I'm going to keep this rule and do it every single time I want to connect things.
即以0为锚点的树 我将遵循这个规则 并在每次连接事物时都这样做
So here's another example to make sure that's absolutely crystal clear.
这里有另一个例子 确保这一点绝对清晰
I have two groups.
我有2个item
This is the group with boss 0.
这是老板为0的item
This is the group with boss 6.
这是老板为6的item
And the question for you is, if you would like to link 3 and 8, you want to connect 3 and 8, how do you connect it in a way that creates a shorter tree?
还有一个问题 如果你想把3和8连接起来 你想以一种创建更短树的方式连接3和8 你会怎么做
Don't create the big tree.
不要创建大树
Create the smaller one.
创建小的那个
And remember, there are two choices.
记住 有两个选择
And remember, you always want to hang the smaller tree underneath the larger tree.
记住 你总是想把较小的树挂在较大的树下面
So to kind of speed through it a little bit, because of our fantastic mic issues, I look.
为了快速处理一下 因为我们的麦克风出了点问题 我看
Well, do I need to change 3?
我需要改变3吗
Remember, no.
记住 不要
We don't change 3.
我们不改变3
We don't change 8.
我们不改变8
If we do that, we disconnect sections.
如果我们这样做 我们会断开部分连接
We don't like that.
我们不喜欢那样
The nodes get lonely.
节点感到孤独
We don't want nodes to be lonely.
我们不希望节点孤独
So instead, remember, what we do is we need to climb the tree and say, 3, your boss is 0.
相反地 请记住 我们要做的是要爬树并说 3 你的老板是0
And I climb the tree here, 8, your boss is 6.
我在这里爬树 8 你的老板是6
0 and 6, you cannot both be bosses.
0和6 你们俩不能都是老板
There's too many bosses.
老板太多了
We need to merge you.
我们需要合并你
And again, I have to choose.
而且 我必须再次选择
Does 6 become a subordinate of 0, or does 0 become a subordinate of 6?
6成为0的下属 还是0成为6的下属
And the rule is, to make our tree short, we're always going to take the smaller tree and hang it underneath the larger tree.
而规则是 为了使我们的树短 我们总是要取较小的树挂在较大的树下面
So I count.
我数一下
This tree has 4 items.
这棵树有4个item
This tree has 6.
这棵树有6个
So we're going to take the 4-item tree and hang it underneath the 6-item tree.
我们要把这个有4个item的树挂在这个有6个item的树下面
That's what I want.
这就是我想要的
So this is the result.
这就是结果
I'm going to take 6.
我要拿6个
You're no longer the boss.
你不再是老板了
You now belong to 0.
现在你属于0
And now these trees are merged.
现在这些树已经合并了
They become one big team.
他们变成了一个大item
OK.
Great.
太好了
So to implement this, we now have to keep track of size.
因此 为了实现这个目标 我们现在需要跟踪大小
And one clever way to keep track of size, and you will get to figure this out when you do the lab, is instead of using negative 1 to represent that you are the boss, you're actually going to use negative 4 to represent the negative represents you're the boss, and the 4 represents that you have four people in your team.
一个巧妙的跟踪大小的方法 你在做实验室时会发现 就是使用负4代替负1来表示你是老大 负数表示你是老大 4表示你的item有4个人
Or if I put negative 2, the negative means you're the boss, and the 2 means that there are two people in your team.
或者 如果我用-2 负数意味着你是老大 2表示你的item有2个人
And by adding these extra numbers, this allows me to remind myself, if I want to connect 6 and 0, well, 0 is the smaller one.
通过添加这些额外的数字 这让我提醒自己 如果我想连接6和0 0是较小的那个
It's got two things in its team.
它的队伍里有两样东西
6 is larger.
6更大
It's got four things in its team.
它的队伍里有四样东西
So I need to hang the 0, which is one of the bosses, underneath 6, which is the other boss.
我需要把0挂在6下面 0是其中一个老大 6是另一个老大
So by keeping track of the size of the teams, I can always hang the smaller tree
通过跟踪队伍的大小 我可以始终把较小的树
underneath the larger tree.
挂在较大的树下面
OK.
Dang, I'm going to run out of time.
哎呀 时间快不够了
Maybe I'll do a little bit of this next time, too.
也许下次我会再做一点这样的事情
So to quickly finish, at least wait a quick union, now we need to think about how fast this is.
为了快速完成 至少等一个快速的联合 现在我们需要考虑这有多快
I guess I'll quickly pause if you have questions.
我想如果你有问题 我会很快停下来
Sorry, this lecture always runs a little bit long.
抱歉 这个讲座总是会有点长
OK.
So the key idea, the thing you really have to know to really make this work, is whenever you have two trees and you want to merge them, you should always take the smaller tree and hang it underneath the larger tree.
关键的想法 你真的必须知道的东西 是每当你有两棵树想要合并它们时 你应该始终选择较小的树并将其挂在较大的树下面
There are two bosses.
有两位老板
Which boss gets to stay and be the true, ultimate, big, mega boss?
哪一位老板能留下 成为真正的、终极的、大、超级老板呢
It's the one that had the larger group to begin with.
是那位一开始就有较大item的老板
In this case, 0 had the larger group, so it got to stay as the big, ultimate boss.
在这种情况下 0号老板有较大的item 所以它留下来成为大、终极老板
And 6, you had the smaller group.
而6号 你的item较小
So you had to be merged into the other group.
你必须合并到另一个item
So 6, you're no longer the boss.
所以6号 你不再是老板了
You hang under 0.
你挂在0下面
And to keep track of how big the teams are, because you're going to have to write this in Java, to keep track of how big each team is,
为了追踪item的规模 因为你将要用Java写这个 为了追踪每个item有多大
when you have an item that's the root, instead of just writing negative 1 to say you're the boss, you should write negative 4.
当你有一个作为根的item时 不要只写负1表示你是老板 你应该写负4
To say negative means you're the boss, and 4 means you have four items in your team.
负数表示你是老板 4表示你的item有4个item
And then negative 2 means you're the boss.
然后负2表示你是老板
You have two items in your team.
你的item有2个item
And all the positive numbers work like before.
所有正数仍然像以前一样工作
So 9, you belong to item 8.
所以9 你属于item 8
8, you belong to item 6.
8 你属于第6项
6, you're the boss.
6 你是老板
And you have four things in your team.
而且你的item有四件事
All that's the same.
所有的都一样
So that's how you might implement it.
你可能是这样实现的
So I guess the final thing I'll have time for today is, how fast is this operation now that I have constrained you to always taking the smaller tree and hanging it underneath the larger tree?
我猜今天我还有时间做的最后一件事是 现在我限制你总是采取较小的树并将其悬挂在较大的树下 这个操作有多快
So remember.
记住
We now take smaller trees, hang them underneath larger trees.
现在我们采用更小的树 把它们挂在更大的树下面
It turns out, and this is not going to be obvious at all, but you can go home and play with it a little bit.
原来 这一点一点都不明显 但你可以回家玩一玩 稍微摸索一下
It turns out that if you enforce this constraint, that the smaller tree must always become the subordinate of the larger tree.
原来 如果你强制执行这个约束 即较小的树必须始终成为较大树的从属
That is, if you have two bosses, the weaker boss, the one with fewer items, is going to lose and get merged into the larger one, the larger group.
也就是说 如果你有两个老板 较弱的老板 也就是拥有较少item的那个 将会输掉并合并到较大的老板 即较大的item中
then it turns out that those ugly trees from before, remember, the whole reason why we're doing this is because this was super annoying.
然后事实证明 之前的那些丑陋的树 记得吗 我们之所以这样做是因为那真的很让人讨厌
Look at it.
看一下
It's so gross.
真恶心
It turns out we want to avoid this.
我们要避免这个
And it turns out that if you always hang the smaller tree underneath the larger tree, that is, the smaller boss always loses and becomes a subordinate of the bigger boss, then what you will get is you will never get structures like this.
事实证明 如果你总是让较小的树成为较大树的下级 也就是说 较小的老板总是输给较大的老板 成为其下属 那么你得到的结构就永远不会像这样
The weighted quick union rule makes this structure impossible.
加权快速合并规则使得这种结构成为不可能
And I encourage you to try it. at home to convince yourselves.
我鼓励你们在家尝试 以便自己确信
But I'll show you a quick demo, which is, turns out, if you have one item, this is the worst possible structure you can make.
但我会给你们快速演示一下 如果你有一个item 这是你能创建的最糟糕的结构
If you have two items, this is the worst possible structure.
如果你有2个item 这是最糟糕的结构
If you have three items, this is the worst possible structure.
如果你有3个item 这是最糟糕的结构
or I guess I haven't shown it on the slide.
或者我猜我没有在幻灯片上展示过它
But it turns out if you have three items, you will never get a case where the third item hangs underneath the one.
但事实证明 如果你有3个item 你永远不会出现第3个item悬挂在一个item下面的情况
This is not possible.
这是不可能的
You can go home, you can try it, play with some Connect operations.
你可以回家 你可以尝试一下 玩一些连接操作
There will never be a case where you have three items in a chain.
永远不会出现一个链中有3个item的情况
And it turns out that the smallest data structure with four items looks like this.
事实证明 具有4个item的最小数据结构看起来像这样
There's no other way to get four items with taller height.
要想得到高度较大的4个item 没有其他办法
It has to look like this.
它必须看起来像这样
If you don't believe me, go home and try it.
如果你不相信我 回家试试看
And it turns out that's what it looks like.
结果证明就是这个样子
If I have four items, this is the worst case.
如果我有4个item 这就是最坏的情况
So it's actually two copies of this union together.
实际上是将两个副本联合在一起
This is the worst possible case for four items.
这是4个item的最坏情况
How about eight items?
8个item怎么样
What's the worst possible case for eight items?
8个item的最坏情况是什么
And again, go home, play with it, take eight items, connect them in any order you want following the weighted rule.
然后 回家 玩玩它 拿8个item 按照加权规则随意连接它们
And you'll find out that with eight items, turns out the worst thing you could do with eight items, the worst case, is to actually make another copy of this four-item data structure and union these two.
你会发现 对于8个item 最糟糕的事情是 实际上制作另一个4个item数据结构的副本 并将这两个合并
This is the worst possible case for eight items.
这是8个item的最坏情况
And for 16 items, that's the worst possible case, and so forth.
对于16个item 那就是最坏的情况 依此类推
So although I haven't proven it to you, and I've encouraged you to go home and try it on your own,
虽然我没有向你证明 但我鼓励你回家自己尝试一下
It turns out that the worst-case height, if you use the weighted quick union rule, is log n. How do I know it's log n?
原来 如果你使用加权快速联合规则 最坏情况下的树高是log n 我怎么知道是log n呢
Well, one way to do it is to look at the table and say, if this is n, the number of items, and this is the height, and I look for a function,
有一种方法是查看表格并说 如果这是n 物品的数量 这是高度 我寻找一个函数
where I can put in these numbers and get these numbers, it turns out the correct function is log n. Log of 16 is 4.
在这个函数中 我可以输入这些数字并得到这些数字 结果证明正确的函数是log n 16的对数是4
Log of 8 is 3.
8的对数是3
Log of 4 is 2.
4的对数是2
That's the function that satisfies my pattern.
这是满足我的模式的函数
Another way to see it is to note that every time I double the size of the input, the runtime gets slower by 1.
另一种看待它的方式是注意到每次将输入大小加倍时 运行时间减慢1
So if it's the case that my input doubles and the runtime, the function, gets slower by 1, that's logarithmic performance.
如果我的输入加倍而运行时间增加1 那就是对数性能
It's OK if you don't get it.
如果你不懂也没关系
We will do lots more asymptotics so you do get it.
我们会讲很多渐近符号 这样你就能理解了
So I guess I will have to finish this next time, unfortunately.
我想我只能在下次完成这个了 不幸的是
But just know that we came up with four different ideas for how to show people the data structure of disjoint sets.
但要知道 我们提出了四种不同的想法来展示不相交集的数据结构
And the choice of data structure had big effects on how fast and how easy it is to code.
而数据结构的选择对编码的速度和易用性有很大影响
OK, I'll see you next time.
下次见
Sorry for all the technical difficulties.
抱歉 由于一些技术问题
I hope your midterm went well and you had fun.
希望你的期中考试顺利 玩得开心
I'll see you next time.
下次见
I want to have more fun.
我想要更多乐趣